What's up, Dolph fans, and welcome back
into the Baptist Hill studios for
another edition of Dolphins HQ here in
Miami Gardens. And we have a bit of a
first here for Dolphins HQ joining us, I
think, is our first ever AllPro, Aaron
Brewer, joins us on the show today. I'm
curious what that process is like when
they inform you. Like, is it a phone
call? Does someone send you an email?
And how did you feel when you found out
you were second team all pro this year?
>> I don't got social media right now. I'm
doing a fast. And so I woke up in the
morning, probably like 10:00 after a
long night, you know what I'm saying?
And Pat had called me in the morning. He
had changed flight. He called me. He
talking about, "Congratulations, bro."
I'm like, "What are you talking about?"
And I did. I didn't know I was named all
pro, bro. I literally like found out I
was all pro from Pat calling me the
morning after and just sending text
messages like really like did not know.
I wanted to talk more about your play
this season, obviously while we have you
on the show, but we've highlighted you
on the show, Brew, more times than I can
count. So, the world knows what Travis's
favorite A-on Brewer blocks are, but I'm
curious about you. There's got to be a
couple out there from this year. There
was so many to pick from, but there's
got to be a couple that stood out to you
this year.
Um, just when we speak on it, I'll say
like come to my say probably my top two
that come to mind is probably it was
against Atlanta and the other was
against the Commanders. You know what
I'm saying? Definitely like one of the
second level blocks. So went against
Atlanta. It was on a little short screen
close to end game almost like silling
like just putting that nail in the
coffin just a statement block. And so it
was out there on Jesse Bass. I think
y'all probably remember that one. So
they're probably one of my top ones. And
then against Washington, I just remember
going into the game because I'm playing
Bobby Wagner and Frankie, like two top
tier linebackers, like some of the best
in the league behind Jordan Brooks, you
know what I'm saying? Another pro bowler
we got. And so yeah, we're playing Bobby
Wagner and it was at the first play
Bobby Wagner, you know, he's a Hall of
Famer. So I'm in my head before the game
like, "Oh, this a statement game. I need
this." And so I pulled around had
blocked I think I picked up a DB and he
was trying to run over top and I blocked
both of them at the same time and threw
both of them and two knockdowns on one
play first play of the game. So there
was just two two plays that really just
come to my mind. I think of the season
like top blocks. Yeah, there's two of
them.
>> We've broken those plays down on the
show like literally those exact plays
you're talking about there. And we've
had something of a running joke here on
HQ where we always know that Brew did
something special because you would hit
this little skip after a massive block
where you put a guy on his back, you're
20 yards downfield, there goes Hanner
for a big play and you're kind of like
skipping and shaking your head and doing
this whole thing. Is that your natural
reaction to making a play? Do you know
what I'm talking about? Like is that
just how you react after making a big
play?
>> Yeah, I know what you're talking about.
Yeah. Like after after I make a big
play, it's just it's just the energy.
Like that's that's how I'm letting it
all out. like you know somebody making a
big play you flexing hitting your head
or just jumping up and down like just
it's a it's a different kind of feeling
and so when I do make a big play that's
how I let it out.
>> We might have to uh start tracking Bruce
skips next year like we'll have a
running tally and keep that as a stat
for for offensive line play. Maybe we
can put it across the rest of the league
and that's how they can be how they can
determine the protector of the year
which you're in the running for that as
well.
>> Hey we need to start count something.
Start counting knockdowns. How many
bodies I get in a year? just hey just
put up a uh every game just count them
just one two like a little ding you know
say like a little bell to knock down
just count them
>> going back a little bit further Brew you
know it it's 2019 going to go ahead and
time travel here the Texas State
football roster has you listed at 270
lbs you go undrafted for me personally
Brew there is nothing better than a guy
going undrafted to AllP pro it's the
proof that football is the ultimate
meritocracy which makes it the best the
best game in the world but I'm curious
If all pro Aaron Brewer could go back in
time and talk to Texas State Aaron
Brewer, what would you tell that young
man?
>> Keep doing exactly what you doing and
turn up a little more.
>> At that point in time, I had went to a
different level of focus. You know what
I'm saying? Cuz it's 2019. I'm coming
off my season. Then I had another
semester in school and then I had to do
pre-draft training as well. And so at
that point in time, like I know I'm 27.
I know I'm underweight. I'm coming from
Texas State. like I got my accolades
behind me from like first seen something
bel. It was like really like taking the
risk on myself at the time and it was a
little scary in the moment because I had
said you know what if I'm going to try
to get to NFL I'm going to put all my
chips in and so if I can go back to him
then like you doing the right thing like
stay on the track you're going and you
got some big things coming in your
future.
>> I love to hear you. It's paid off for
you in a big way. I want to pivot now
and talk a little bit about your
teammates and go to the offensive line
here with Patrick Paul specifically
because Brew that man is an enigma. He
is an introspective intellectual. He
couldn't be a nicer person to me at
least. Then he gets on that field and
does that thing where he like bullies
someone 20 yards down the field and
laughs while he's doing it like these
drive blocks where he's laughing
maniacally. And you know Pat as well as
anybody out there. Can you just tell our
audience about your teammate and what
makes him a special player but also a
special person? Uh Pat, he just Pat is
is his own individual. Like if you know
Pat, Pat Pat is nicest guy ever. Great
guy, but also he he he he know how to
get to. You know what I'm saying? Great
dude. Life for the party type guy. And
he just he's a dog out there, man. Y'all
seen his tape this year. Like the stuff
he put on tape. Like it's his first year
starting as well. Like a full season. So
he kind of still a rookie. You know what
I'm saying? And for him to have this
full season this year and go out there
and dominate he was like the things he
put on tape
that was next level for a rookie
definitely his fresh start and so the
sky's is limit with Pat.
>> Uh but Devon Achan man like I I I think
I know the answer to the first part of
the question. Is he the best back in
football in your opinion? And then the
second part is why? What makes him the
best back in football? If the answer is
yes.
>> Absolutely. Yes. You know what I'm
saying? Like Devon he he a special
talent. You know what I'm saying? He he
undersized back but the way he run you
couldn't tell that you know what I'm
saying like he fast strong sturdy like
the way he able to stay up and sustain
through blocks and break tackles like
through defense linebackers don't matter
like his balance his speed is crazy he
he's a problem in the run game he's a
problem in the pass game and so like but
is special I don't think many people can
do what he's doing right now
>> well I'm glad you mentioned that that
way because my last question for you is
I kind you know, build up with Pat and
Devon and you talked about Jordan Brooks
earlier. I I want to just close the show
or close the interview here with this
question. What most excites you for the
2026 season for the Miami Dolphins, for
Aaron Brewer. What's the most exciting
thing you're looking forward to for next
season?
>> The guys we have and hopefully a lot of
them come return because of how guys
played this year. Like the things that
we can do next year building off what we
had like that what we found midseason
this year. like you you you grasp that
and enhance it this off seasonason and
come into the season like
next year. Hey man, it can be something
really really special. Really special.
And so I'm just ready to see how we come
in
training camp really before otaas like
the mindset and how we come everything
that lead into this next season. We got
the recipe. seven.
>> Well, we did we did several segments on
this show, Dolphins HQ this year talking
about the young nucleus, the young core
of the Miami Dolphins with you being
right in the middle of that, my friend.
So, there you go. Dolphins all pro
center, Aaron Brewer. Brew, we
appreciate your time today, man. Get
back to your vacation. Get back to
kicking the feet up and uh thanks again
for your time, man.
>> No problem. Appreciate.
>> The Miami Dolphins announced they have
signed John Eric Sullivan to serve as
the team's general manager. Sullivan
brings more than two decades of
experience in scouting and player
evaluation to Miami. most recently
serving as the Packers VP of player
personnel where he spent each of his 22
NFL seasons there in Green Bay. He
helped the Packers [music] win Super
Bowl 45, 10 NFC North Division titles
and 16 playoff appearances during his
tenure with the Packers. Sullivan was a
key part of Packers personnel
departments that acquired players who
combined for more than 15 first team
allpro [music] selections and over 40
Pro Bowl nods. In his role as Green
Bay's vice president of player
personnel, which he held from 2022
[music] to 2025, Sullivan oversaw the
team's college and pro scouting
departments, working in tandem with
general manager [music] Brian Guda, and
collaborating closely with head coach
Matt Laflur. The Packers have reached
the playoffs in three of the last four
seasons [music] while retooling their
roster with talent, with a balanced
approach through the draft, free agency,
and through trades. Now, I looked at
four years as VP of player personnel,
his time there, and made some
observations. Let's go ahead and start
with the draft. And rather than rattle
off a bunch of numbers and rankings, I
just want to identify some trends here.
And if you're looking for all the math
and thought behind this, you can find
all of it on the Draft Time podcast. But
I think it's best distilled down to a
few of these key points. Number one,
over the four years, they made 43 picks.
That's an average of 10.75 draft picks
per year. 17 picks were made on days one
and two, and nine of those picks came at
premium positions. Your quarterbacks,
your receivers, offensive tackles, edge
rushers, and quarterbacks, the most
expensive positions in the National
Football League. There was a big focus
on college playing time as well. Those
43 picks [music] averaged 49 career
games played in college. But there's
more to it. The deeper into the draft
they got, the more they valued playing
time. Days 1 and two, that's rounds 1
through three, averaged right around 41
games played in college. But when they
got to day three, rounds four through 7,
those picks averaged 47 career games
played at the college level. 40% of the
picks were fifthear seniors and 77% of
the picks were in college programs for
four or more years experience. And how
can you argue with those results? Those
day three picks include receiver Romeo
Dobs, who's going to be one of the top
market receivers available this March if
he hits free agency. Zack Tom is a damn
good right tackle who started 55 games
for the Packers over the last three
seasons. Kingsley Ingbari has played
every game in four years as a rotational
rusher and Rasheed Walker a seventh
round tackle has played every game the
last three years for the Packers. That
formula, well, it's working if you
exclude this year's rookie class, which
we do because the impact of a day three
rookie is usually rather minimal. But
the Packers [music] have been consistent
and getting development and pieces in
the door and developing them down the
road for their production throughout the
course of their career. 10 of 24 day
three picks, played 400 plus snaps at
least once in their career. That's a 46%
hit rate on day three. And every single
class we're talking about has produced
at least one core special teams player
for the Packers. This might be my
favorite factoid about the Packers draft
and develop program there with solely in
in in business. Only seven of the 43
picks transferred in college. Three of
those were guys that transferred up in
competition. So only 9% of their draft
picks made a lateral transfer. I know
this old man needs to get on board with
the current college football landscape,
but I kind of like it when the player
finishes what he starts. They drafted 12
players from blueb blood programs, your
Alabamaas, Michigan, Texas, Ohio State,
on and on and on. And 77% of their draft
picks were from power four schools. It's
a lot to digest, I know. But all of this
is to say, I am excited to see what John
Eric Sullivan will bring to the Miami
Dolphins front office. Draft and
develop, baby. You want consistency.
That, my friends, is the path to
sustainability in this league.
Jordan Brooks is an allpro linebacker,
first team for the Miami Dolphins here.
And I'm going to show you five plays
that show you why he had such a great
season to earn that recognition this
year in the national football. Go ahead
and watch right here. Number 20. I want
you to just watch the way he bounces
around his alignment pre- snap. Right
here, we're off the three technique
right here behind Zeke Biggers. We're
going to then see Baker Mayfield make an
adjustment right here. We're going to
kick down inside off the left side of
that three technique. And look at him
just kind of calling some traffic
signals here, telling the defense what's
going to happen because he knows at the
snap of the ball where things are going.
I don't know what he sees. I don't know
what he's doing, but he knows exactly
what he's doing. Baker's going to can
the play, make a check. He knows the
assignments right here are here, here,
and this tight end wants to down block
him, and they're going to run the ball
off to the side of the formation. So, he
knows because of this alignment and
scooting over here that he can shoot
this A gap and go make the play before
the Bucks have a chance to hit that down
block on him. If he stays out wide in
his alignment, this tight end has a
better chance to climb right here, cut
him off [music] across the face and
prevent him from getting this gap right
here, which he then goes and makes a TFL
on Bucks running back Bucky Irving. This
is him all year long. Alignment,
assignment, finishing. He has been such
a great player for the Miami Dolphins.
[music] Earn that first team allp pro
linebacker position. Once again, right
here pointing out traffic. What's going
to happen? Zack Cer communicating back
with him right here. Going to jump down
onto the tackle right here and cap him.
And just watch the way he waves through
trash. First off, he knows where the
play is going. Once again, watch the way
he jumps this gap. He knows his run fit,
his assignment right there. He's going
to get down to the trash right here, but
not get himself clogged up to where he
can't get off the pile and make a play.
And he winds up shooting the gap and
making yet another TFL. He is so
alignment, assignment, sound, and he's
so good in the trash in the pile of
bodies to keep himself on his feet to
fight around blocks. He beats blocks
with quickness, with pregame film study,
with his physicality. Every way you can
beat a block, Jordan Brooks does it.
It's why he makes the most tackles in
the NFL. That's why he makes a bevy of
tackles for loss. He is just so
productive each and every Sunday. Once
again, right here off the weak side of
the formation. A big heavy package right
here for the Buffalo Bills. Actually,
we're [music] on the strong side here,
but we're going to run the ball off the
weak side of the formation. Try to cut
this thing backside right here. Once
again, Jordan Brooks knows his
assignment. He knows he has this C gap
that he can shoot right here because
they're going to try to wield this this
additional tight end right here down
into the uh into the insert on ify
Malafu. And it's going to give Brooks a
free run, which they're thinking that
maybe they can press this thing
playside. The running back has other
ideas because Kenneth Grant stacks it
up. Jordan Phillips stacks it up. Zeke
Bigger sets his edge right there. And
they [music] have to force the running
back into a backside cut. And Jordan
Brooks is already there because he knows
where the play is going because he
learned it on Wednesday in film study
and practices all week with high
intensity. That's why he makes so many
plays. Preparation, physicality,
violence, speed. He does everything
[music] on the football field. Those are
three rundown stops in the back field
for Jordan Brooks. Let's go ahead and
take a look at some playmaking right
here. A sack. And there's not a lot to
this to break down. He knows which gap
he wants to shoot. Does a good job
disguising his blitz, playing off the
football right here, not giving any
indication. He's going to rush this gap
right here. The running back tries to
step up and pick him up. And pass pro.
H. Good luck, Bon Robinson. That's not
really going to work out for you against
that player against a first team allp
pro linebacker like Jordan Brooks just
runs it down. Bradley Chub condenses the
edge, gives him the run off the side,
off the edge, runs the running back over
and tackles Kirk Cousins for a big sack.
So, sack production, TFL production. How
about in the passing game when he's in
coverage? This one a little bit more
in-depth of a breakdown. So, what I want
to show you off the top right here is
the Dolphins are in a pressure look. And
what that I mean by that, they're only
going to bring these four guys. But
because this safety winds up capping
this slot receiver right here, that's a
pressure look. With this linebacker, he
could possibly come. Sometimes when you
see a safety capped over a receiver like
that, they're going to bring the second
level player on the pressure look. And
then Jordan Brooks right here, that's a
pressure look to me. He's actually
showing that he's going to blitz. Winds
up backing out. We're going to get cover
two. We're going to get half field. half
field underneath underneath. Here's your
hole player and then we're going to play
the hook zone with Brooks and Tyrell
Dodson. So, bring four, seven man in
coverage, cover two. And what Jordan
Brooks has right here, he's going to
drop to the sticks. He has a landmark.
He wants to get to the sticks and kind
of play things top down [music] right
here. What I want you to watch is how
valuable he is and covering all of this
space and really helping the entire
structure of the coverage. Because this
quarterback, Rousul Douglas, is playing
this cloud in cover two. He knows the
inside underneath route is vulnerable.
So, we're going to get depth and make
sure that Mike Giki, Bengals tight end,
is not going to stack us vertically
[music] here. We're going to get depth
and cover that and match it, but also
have eyes on this receiver. So, if Joe
Burrow does want to throw that ball hot
and quick, he can drive on it and cut it
down for a short gain and give us a
third and medium for the Bengals. But
Joe Burrow opts to throw the seam route
because he knows Jordan Brooks wants
[music] to drive that. So, Brooks has
the ability to flip the hips and run
vertical and run with Cassiki and make a
play on the football. I cannot express
to you how good how good of a play this
is from all that he has to process from
the the mindset, the preparation, the
physical nature like the the hips to
flip him like that and run [music]
vertically to get a hand on the
football. It just showcases everything
about his game, the talent, the
production, the uh preparation,
everything about his leadership, who he
is as a person on all five of these
plays, but this one in particular,
Jordan Brooks earned the first team
allpro linebacker nod the NFL this year
because of great production across all
three phases of the game. never leaves
the field. Big- time leader, Jordan
Brooks, one of the best players in the
entire National Football League.
So, this segment is going to be ever
evolving, a living, breathing document,
if you will, and that comes with some
caveats on top of the already disclaimer
I just gave you. I want to be very clear
about this. This is a draft board in
January. It's not gonna be the same
draft board I have in April. it will
undoubtedly change and I'll add more as
we get to more players in the process.
What I did for this project was go down
ESPN's Jordan Reed's top 50 players. I
watched the top 20, wrote scouting
reports, and rank them accordingly.
Since the Dolphins pick 11th, we're
going to go over my top 11. Sound
[music] good? Let's go ahead and jump
right in. Let's do this thing in rapid
succession here. First things first,
Caleb DS can play any position in the
back seven. He's my top player. He
played a safety nickel combination at
Ohio State and his combo of quick twitch
and preparation which produces fast
react instincts makes him such a clean
prospect. Great tackler, reads his keys,
finds the football. To me, he's the best
player this draft has to offer. He's not
far above Arll Reese, who is my number
two player who I think could be a
game-wrecking edge in the NFL. He plays
off the football as well, but he's a
powerful player with elite technique and
rare twitch. Two corners and a tackle
round out my top five. Mansor Delane has
similar traits to Downs in terms of his
instincts and physical traits to get to
the exact [music] moment to get to
something the exact moment that he sees
it on the field. Ultra competitive, long
speed, terrific in any man or zone
technique, and he's just a ball player.
He shows up all over the tape. Now,
Tennessee's Jer McCoy, probably the best
man-to-man cover corner in this class.
He did tear his ACL that cost him the
entire 2025 season, but his 24 tape is
as good as it gets. Francis Maui Goa is
the tackle that splits those two corners
at number four. Talk about set and
forget prospects. Some will talk about
him kicking his head to guard, but I
think he could play anywhere on your
line because of a special ability to
sink and bend at the knees, absorb
against power, but also the foot
quickness to react inside or outside.
He's thickly built and drives guys off
the football in the running game. The
sixth player on my board might be my
favorite entire in the entire draft. The
league pendulum is swinging back towards
power football after the downfield
scoring era. And tight ends that can win
as eligible in the passing game, but
also be a focal point of your outside
running game and then insert inside to
boot. Those are the true game changers.
That's Kenyan Sadik from Oregon. Good in
line, dynamic playmaker, field
stretcher, run after catch. He does
everything. Let's go through number
seven through 11 here really quickly.
Linebacker Sunonny Styles. We talked
about him on the show before. Former
safety converted to linebacker with the
athletic ability to prove it. He does
not miss tackles. He arrives with
violence. Three down skill set player.
Ruben Bane at Miami is the most powerful
player in this entire draft. And he
combines that with polished hand usage.
The Hurricanes use him to stack the run
to win around the edge to loop inside on
rush games and he is highly effective at
everything that he does. Mai Lemon isn't
the biggest target in football, but if
it's in his vicinity, he's going to come
down with the ball. competitive in the
line of scrimmage, at the break point,
at the catch point. And while he varies
every route just a little bit, they all
look the same and it makes him
impossible to cover one-on-one. He
doesn't blow you away with the
measurables, but he'll be a,200 yard
receiver year in year out of USC.
Jeremiah Love is a contact, balance,
power, speed running back that has
vision and burst to hit home runs from
Notre Dame. He's in the top 10 as well.
And David Bailey is a get off bendy
explosive rusher who tilted the
protection plan against te for Texas
Tech rather every single game this year.
He's got rare twitch and finishes his
pressures with game impact plays each
and every week. So the point of this
exercise is that Miami is in position to
land an absolute stud here at the 11th
pick. This list didn't even include two
quarterbacks of which we'll probably see
at least two of them come off the board
before this spot. So, we'll have you
covering all of this stuff here on
Dolphins HQ on Drive Time and across all
of our channels for this year's draft. A
draft in which Miami has five picks in
the top 100.
That will do it here for this episode of
Dolphins HQ from the Baptist Health
Studios. Don't forget to check out the
Drive Time podcast hosted by yours
truly, available three days [music] per
week in the offseason wherever you get
your podcast. Subscribe to the Dolphins
YouTube channel for all offseason
content and media availabilities. We
hope to see you back here very soon.